

# Alejandro Berrío Marín

+57 313 708 1557
alejo86a@gmail.com
Medellín / Colombia
linkedin.com/in/alejo86a
twitter.com/alejo86adev
github.com/alejo86a

Backend developer

# SKILLS javascript typescript nodejs expressis java Java EE Html/css Angular Angularis Php/laravel SCRUM Scala Ionic

## EDUCATION

#### **Systems Engineering**

ITM (Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano) 6° semester (actual)

# Diploma course in advance architecture with microservices and devops

UdeA (Universidad de Antioquia) 2018

# **Systems Engineering**

UdeA (Universidad de Antioquia) 8° semester (in pause)

#### Systems Technique

SENA (Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje) 2011

# ABOUT ME

I am a developer passionate about new technologies who loves to learn all kinds of technologies in a self-taught way. Entrepreneurship lover from my own personal projects to my work experience. Obsessed with meeting goals quickly under the principles of quality, extensibility, security, reusability, and code readability

## EXPERIENCE

# Publicis Global Delivery (prodigious)

Senior Principal Software Engineer/San Francisco, California / 2021-2022

- Backend development mainly with nodejs and other technologies such as java and react
- working in internals projects at knex, springboot, react, strapi,
- talent interviewer with nodejs profile.

## **BairesDevSoftware**

Development Engineer / San Francisco, California / 2021

outsourcing and software development company that allowed me to be part of two interesting projects

 Instructure: as a backend developer in nodejs waitr app: As a backend developer in nodejs and devops.

#### **Rapicredit**

software engeneer / Bogotá, Colombia / 2020-2021

fintech startup in charge of making small loans to unbanked people.

- Development frontend with angular in charge of implementing the best practices in the development.
- Development backend creation of endpoint with java spring boot and the drools rule manager.

#### Intermediate backend developer Rappi S.A.S./Bogota, Colombia/2018-2020

 Development of rappiPay an alternative to send, receive money or pay without using a bank card.

#### **Development consultant**

SETI S.A.S./Medellín, Colombia/2016-2020 Full stack developer in the following projects:

- Develop a platform for the management of proposals, company commercials, sales and follow up projects. This project was developed in Angular, Java EE and Oracle.
- Platform for the quote and sale of car insurance and company insurance developed in GuideWire, Angular and Scala.

# CERTIFICATES

#### IBM Cloud basics on platzi (2018)

Basic of architecture, micro services and artificial intelligence as well as the installation and IBM cloud application deployment.

### **SCALA intensive course (2018)**

Dictated by seven4n.

#### Jenkins CI and DevOps (2017)

Master Jenkins Build and Test Automation in 2 Hours. Hand-on DevOps, CICD, Jenkins Pipeline, Jenkins on AWS.

#### Call for discovery of apps.co (2016)

Which I was a finalist and I acquired Marketing insights, customer discovery, and some talks on software development mainly in doing a quick MVP.

# Startup weekend Medellín "INTERNET OF THINGS" (2015)

Event of entrepreneurship in which for 3 days of continuous work in the city of Medellín the aim was to develop an innovative idea within an interdisciplinary team.

#### Fintech challenge (2015)

Event of bank entrepreneurship in which for 3 days of continuous work in the city of Bogota the aim was to develop an innovative idea within an interdisciplinary team.

# Application development course for IOS (2013)

Dictated by arunovo and rutaN.

### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelancer

Freelancer/Colombia/ 2012-2016

Develop web pages in HTML and CSS to promote and show small products and services of small companies.

- Design and layout
- Logo construction and photo editing
- Deploy and maintain the website in time.

## Founder and CEO

Peiname.co/Colombia/ 2016

- Founder my own start up
- Marketing
- Customer discovery
- MVP development (android and ios app)